# PATRICIA SMITH-BOYE ESQ. OTR/L

13 Crescent Street, Stow, MA 01775 Cell: 978-273-6133 attysmithboye@gmail.com

### QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

A highly accomplished attorney with five years of civil litigation and criminal defense specifically in the areas of debt defense, contracts, family law, education law, special education law, landlord tenant disputes, mold toxic tort, and personal injury. Effective time management skills, effective organization skills, and ability to communicate with opposing counsel, witnesses, and insurance adjustors. A proven, experienced manager and effective team member in health care as an Occupational Therapist since 1989. Expert knowledge of physical anatomy and physiology, orthopedics, neurology as it pertains to injuries and rehabilitation. Able to respond quickly and accurately to team leadership needs while serving innovative therapy to patients from pediatric through elderly population. Thorough knowledge of Medicare, Mass Health, Social Security Disability, and Americans with Disability Act. Experienced in trial preparation and all phases of trial to appeal level.

#### **LICENSES**

Attorney: licensed in Massachusetts in good standing since 2009.

Occupational Therapist: licensed in Massachusetts in good standing since 1995. In Florida: 1989-1995

# **Work History**

**Attorney at Law**: 01/2011 to Current

Solo Practice and Of Counsel – 13 Crescent Street, Stow, MA 01775

Developed strategies and arguments in preparation for presentation of cases.

Interpreted laws, rulings and regulations for individuals and businesses.

Analyzed probable outcomes of cases using knowledge of legal precedents.

Managed all trial preparation for case litigation.

Filed all case pleadings in a timely manner.

Creatively formulated trial techniques that specifically pertained to each case.

Explained available courses of action and possible repercussions of cases to clients.

Active defense for clients in collection proceedings.

Assisted clients with drawing up corporation documents for a start up LLC.

Educated parents in 504 accommodations and Individualized Education Plans.

Advocated pro bono for parents with respect to their children in public school.

Filed modifications for child support and /or visitation with Middles ex and Worcester Probate and Family.

Reviewed contracts. Drafted contracts between persons and businesses.

**Associate Attorney**, 03/2009 to 12/2010

Schyberg, Casey, & Carlson, P.C. – 11 Pleasant Street, Worcester, MA 01602

Drafted pleadings, discovery, briefs, memoranda, and correspondences. Managed documents produced in litigation and investigation, including document inventory, and maintained the integrity of the originals and copy sets. Assisted lead attorneys with creating binders for trial. Conducted extensive legislative research. Solid research skills for each case.

Occupational Therapist: 1989-2011

Evaluated and treated a wide range of conditions, including chronic and acute pain, disc prolapse, whiplash, dislocations, arthritis, Multiple Sclerosis, Parkinson's, stroke, and neuropathies. Increased weekly average patient visit volume by approximately 100% through improved scheduling.Managed a high-volume case loads and organized the daily schedules of assistants and patients. Planned individually-designed treatment programs to restore, maintain and improve physical functioning, alleviate pain and prevent disability. Educated student interns in therapy techniques, documentation and

## **Education**

J.D.: Focus on Criminal Law/ Prosecution and Defense, Civil Litigation, 2008

Massachusetts School of Law - 500 Federal Street, Andover, MA01810

insurance verification.

**Activities**: Student Bar Association

Bachelor of Science: Occupational Therapy, 1989

Florida International University - 11200 SW 8th St, Miami, FL 33174

#### **BarAdmissions**

Admitted to the Massachusetts Bar in 2009.

Admitted to the United States Federal Court, First Circuit, Massachusetts in 2013.

### Community

Active in ProBonoassistancetoparentsfortheirchildren's Individual Education Plans and 504

Accommodations and Pro Bono assistance to our local firefighters.

Active in Fundraising for a local charity, Compassionate Care ALS.

Guest Lecturer at American Society for Pain Management Nursing's annual Pain Management dinner and guest

lecturer for Newton Wellesley Hospital's Pain Management Program September Pain Month Rounds, 2012.

Active in assisting the Brotherhood Ride in a bicycle ride from Florida to Boston, September 2015, to raise

money for their fallen brothers and sisters of police and fire.